buzzillions.com 2019-06-26

# Privacy Policy | PowerReviews

##### **Last Updated June 24, 2019**

Thank you for visiting this website (the “Site”) presented to you by PowerReviews, Inc. (“PowerReviews,” “we,” or “us”). Your privacy is important to us. As such, we provide this privacy policy (this “Policy”) explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected, used and disclosed by this Site, our product reviews and ratings services (“Review Service”) and among our network of affiliated and operated review services, which includes any online or mobile websites, applications or digital services owned, operated or offered by, on behalf of, or in conjunction with PowerReviews or its affiliates through which this Privacy Policy appears (each a “Service,” collectively the “Services”).  The Review Service is provided both through the Site and through third party sites via a connection to PowerReviews API or framing techniques as described below (“Third Party Sites”).

PowerReviews affiliates and subsidiaries include Viewpoints, LLC and PowerReviews UK Ltd.

We encourage you (“user” or “visitor”) to read this Policy carefully before providing any personal information on the Site or Review Service. **By visiting our Site and/or using the Review Service, you are accepting the practices described in this Policy:**

  * EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield
  * Information We Collect
  * Third Party Sites
  * Cookies, Web Beacons, and Similar Technologies
  * How Do We Use the Information We Collect
  * Disclosure of Information
  * Your Choices and Access
  * Cross-Border Transfers
  * Use of Services By Minors
  * Security
  * Changes to This Policy
  * Dispute Resolution
  * Questions and Contact Information

* * *

### EU-U.S. PRIVACY SHIELD AND SWISS-U.S. PRIVACY SHIELD

PowerReviews Inc. and Viewpoints, LLC (collectively, the “PowerReviews US entities”) comply with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively.  PowerReviews US entities have certified to the Department of Commerce that they adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles.  For purposes of the PowerReviews US entities, if there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov/](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome).  The Federal Trade Commission has jurisdiction over our compliance with the Privacy Shield.

* * *

### INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We collect “personal information” about users of the Site and the Review Service in the normal course of our business. As used in this Policy, “personal information” is information that identifies or is capable of being associated with an identifiable person. Examples of personal information include, but are not limited to, a user’s name, email address, or phone number. Most of the personal information we receive comes directly from users who register on the Site, use the Review Service or who otherwise voluntarily provide information to PowerReviews in connection with various activities on the Site or Review Service. Personal information does not include aggregate, anonymized, or de-identified information (collectively, “Aggregate Information”). “Aggregate Information” is information gathered or generated directly by the use of the Site or Review Service, such as information collected about Site or Review Service users, or a category of services or users, from which any personal information has been removed. An example of Aggregate Information would be a report stating that forty-seven percent of the Site’s registered users have identified themselves as male.

**Site** : The information you submit at registration on the Site may include, without limitation, name phone number, and e-mail address. We may also collect other types of information during registration or in connection with your other activities on the Site, such as demographic information (including, without limitation, your age, sex and/or gender identity, occupation, interests, location, and income) and information about or contained in postings you make in forums or any other interactive areas of the Site, your answers to surveys, your participation in sweepstakes, contests, games and promotional offers; and in any email request you send us for any reason (such as to request customer service or provide us with comments or feedback).

**Review Service** : Through the Review Service, you may submit star ratings, reviews, comments, photos, videos, questions, and other user-generated content (collectively, “UGC”).  Any UGC you submit may be used for advertising purposes and posted to publicly-facing websites, including other websites across the Internet and on the PowerReviews network, in addition to the website that you originally submitted the UGC. Accordingly, please do not post anything that you do not want to share with the general public (for example, financial information, social security number, etc.). In addition, the UGC that you submit may be used for other advertising, analytic and statistical purposes including, for example, product improvement, benchmarking (e.g. where various products/services or categories of products/services are compared against each other or against the market as a whole), sentiment analysis (e.g. using the data from multiple reviews it is possible to determine how consumers as a whole feel about a product/service), and online behavioral advertising.  We may also collect other types of information in connection with your activities on the Review Service, such as demographic information (including, without limitation, your age, weight, size, hair color, sex, occupation, interests, location, and income) and information about or contained in postings you make in forums or any other interactive areas of the Review Service, your answers to surveys, your participation in sweepstakes, contests, games and promotional offers; and in any email request you send us for any reason (such as to provide us with comments or feedback). In order to submit UGC, you may have to create an account with the PowerReviews’ client whose products, services or goods you are reviewing or rating. During the course of creating an account, you may be asked to submit information, such as but not limited to, your name, email address, phone number, and other data (collectively, “Consumer Account Info”).  The Consumer Account Info may be collected by both PowerReviews and the applicable PowerReviews’ client. To further understand how the PowerReviews’ client to whom you have submitted UGC and Consumer Account Info will use such data, please consult the terms and conditions of that client’s website (e.g. privacy policy).

We automatically collect some information when you use the Site or Review Service. We log your IP address. If you reached the Site by clicking on a link or advertisement on another site, we also log that information. This helps us understand our users’ interests and maximize our online exposure. Please see Cookie, Web Beacons, and Similar Technologies below for additional information.

* * *

### THIRD PARTY SITES

The Review Service may be displayed on or through Third Party Sites through a connection to PowerReviews API or with the use of inline frame or other framing techniques. We may collect personal information in stand alone Write a Review pages, framed pages or content located on or provided by Third Party Sites. When you submit personal information to us in this manner, it is treated as personal information under this Policy. The collection and use of personal information by the Third Party Site directly (i.e., outside of the Review Service Write a Review pages or framed pages) is governed separately by the privacy policy of such site.

* * *

### COOKIES, WEB BEACONS, AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES

We may use cookies to identify Site and Review Service users and to customize user experiences on the Site and Review Service. Unless you provide your email address to us, our cookies contain no personally identifiable information about you. If you have provided your email address to us, however, our cookies may be used to identify you. We use cookies to help us understand how visitors use (and to help us to improve) the Site and Review Service. You may refuse to accept cookies from us by following the procedures specific to your Web browser. If you do so, it may limit your use of some services on the Site or Review Service. **To learn more about our cookie policy,[click here](https://www.powerreviews.com/ad-and-cookie-policy/)**.

Additionally, we may use, and may allow third parties to use, Web beacons on the Site and Review Service to monitor the effectiveness of advertising or for other legitimate purposes. Web beacons, also known as “Web bugs,” are small, graphic images on Web pages or Web-based documents or in email messages that allow us or third parties to monitor who is visiting the Site or Review Service. Web beacons collect the IP address of the computer that the Web beacon is sent to, the URL of the page the Web beacon comes from and the time it was viewed. Web beacons may be linked to your personal information.

* * *

### HOW DO WE USE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We use the information we collect to:

  * Contact you for administrative purposes or provide you with customer service from either PowerReviews or the PowerReviews’ client
  * Provide services to our clients
  * Complete transactions requested by you or to verify that you have submitted a review to our Review Service
  * Respond to any questions, problems or complaints, or request feedback
  * Send you marketing communications if you have submitted your email address through the Site, as permitted by applicable law
  * Organize the Site and Review Service to better serve you, customize or develop our products and services, and market research
  * Send you emails pertaining to our verification process, our policies, and content that you submit
  * Investigate and help prevent potentially unlawful or fraudulent activity or activity that threatens the network or otherwise violates the Usage Agreement

Personal information provided on our Site or through the Review Service may be linked together or merged with other personal information we obtain about you so that PowerReviews and our clients may better understand your needs and inform you about our products or services and those of our business partners. In addition, if we receive personal information from third parties with whom we have business relationships, we may combine this information with the other personal information we maintain about you. In either case, this Policy governs this information.

* * *

### DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION

We do not rent, sell or disclose personal information to third parties without your prior consent, except as described in this privacy policy. We may share personal information when we have your consent to do so, when required by law, when required to protect our rights or property, as necessary to complete a transaction you have requested, or for marketing purposes. We may disclose personal information we collect from you to our affiliates or subsidiaries; however, if we do so, their use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information will be subject to this Policy. We reserve the right to use and disclose any non-personal information that we collect. We may use third party service providers to assist us with the administration of the Site or Review Service or to perform other services for us, including transaction processing and sending emails.

If you provide us with personal information through a Third Party Site, we may share such information with such Third Party Site for their internal business purposes. In addition, we may also share personal information with third parties for such third parties’ (or other third parties’) marketing purposes; however, we provide you with the choice of opting-out of such disclosures (please see “Choice and Access” below).

We may use third parties, called third-party ad servers or network advertisers, to deliver ads to you on our behalf. These third-party ad servers may use cookies, web beacons or other technology to collect non-personally identifiable information about your visits to our Site or the Review Service in order to use it to present advertisements that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice or whether you can opt out of having this information used by third-party ad servers to provide targeted ads, please [visit here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1).

Information about our users, the Site and the Review Service is a business asset of PowerReviews. Therefore, information about our users, including personal information, will be disclosed as part of any (a) merger or acquisition, (b) creation of a separate business to provide the Site or our Review Service, or to provide other services or fulfill products; (c) debt financing, sale or pledge of company assets, or (d) insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personal information would be transferred as one of PowerReviews’ business assets.

We may release personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law (e.g., a lawful subpoena, warrant or court order); to respond to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements; to enforce or apply our policies or any other agreement with a user; to initiate, render, bill, and collect for amounts owed to us; to protect our rights or property; to protect our users from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of our Site or its services; to enforce contest, sweepstakes, promotions, or game rules; or if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of records without delay.

PowerReviews may be liable for appropriate onward transfers of personal data to third parties.

### YOUR CHOICE AND ACCESS

**Opting Out:**

**Cookies** : To delete cookies, simply close your web browser or turn off the computer’s power and the session cookies will be deleted automatically. To delete persistent cookies, you will need to manually delete them through your browser’s setting options. You can disable both session and persistent cookies by adjusting the settings on your web browser. For instructions on disabling cookies, [click here](https://www.usa.gov/optout-instructions). To learn more about our cookie policy, [click here](https://www.powerreviews.com/ad-and-cookie-policy/).

**Marketing Communications** : If you receive marketing communications from a PowerReviews client and would no longer like to be contacted by them, please contact that client directly. If you receive marketing communications from PowerReviews and would no longer like to be contacted by us, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or by sending us an email request to be opted out of marketing communications to [privacy@powerreviews.com](mailto:privacy@powerreviews.com).

**Do-Not-Track** : Currently, our systems do not recognize browser “do-not-track” requests.  You may, however, disable certain tracking as discussed in this section (e.g., by disabling cookies).

**Access and Correction:** If you would like to access, correct, amend, or delete Consumer Account Info or UGC submitted through a PowerReviews client or the Review Service, please contact that client directly. If a PowerReviews client requests us to update or remove your information from our systems, we will respond to their request within thirty (30) days of receipt. PowerReviews recognizes the individual’s right to access their personal data.  If you would like to access, correct, amend or delete any of your personally identifiable information collected or held by PowerReviews through the Site, you may do so through your account settings, if applicable, or by mailing or emailing your request to the below address. We will respond to such requests within thirty (30) days of receipt.

Attn. Privacy  
PowerReviews, Inc.  
1 N. Dearborn, Suite 800  
Chicago, IL 60602  
privacy@powerreviews.com

* * *

### CROSS-BORDER TRANSFERS

PowerReviews may provide the Site and Review Services globally. As a result, we may, subject to law, transfer and store your personal information, in connection with the Site and Review Services, to countries where data protection standards may differ from those in the country where you reside, including to the United States of America. By using the Site and the Review Services, you understand that we may transfer your personal information globally. In certain circumstances, courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies or security authorities in those other countries will be entitled to access your personal information. However, our transfer, storage, and processing of your personal data will at all times be in accordance with this Policy.

* * *

### USE OF SERVICES BY MINORS

We do not intend, and the Site and the Review Service is not designed, to knowingly collect personal information from children. If you are under 13 years old, or if you are between 13 and 16 years old and you live in the European Union or the United Kingdom, you should not register with or otherwise provide personal information to our Site or the Review Service.

* * *

### SECURITY

We use reasonable security measures in an effort to prevent loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control. We cannot, however, guarantee protection of all information against interception, misappropriation, misuse, or alteration, or that your information may be not be disclosed or accessed by accidental circumstances or by the unauthorized acts of others. Furthermore, we have no control over the security of other sites you might visit, interact with or do business with.

* * *

### CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

We will modify this Policy if our privacy practices materially change in the future. We will notify you of such changes only by posting the new policy on our Site or Review Service and indicating at the top of the Policy the date it was last updated. We encourage you to review the Policy each time you visit our Site or Review Service to see if it has been updated since your last visit to make sure you understand how personal information you provide will be used.

* * *

### DISPUTE RESOLUTION

In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, PowerReviews commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact PowerReviews by mail or email as follows:

Attn. Privacy  
PowerReviews, Inc.  
1 N. Dearborn, Suite 800  
Chicago, IL 60602  
privacy@powerreviews.com

PowerReviews has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgement of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/](http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/) for more information and to file a complaint.

Under certain limited conditions and if your complaint is not resolved by PowerReviews or the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a binding arbitration option may be made available to you through the Privacy Shield Panel.

* * *

### QUESTIONS AND CONTACT INFORMATION

If you have any questions, inquiries or complaints about this Policy, or the practices of or your dealings with the Site or Review Service, please contact us at the following address or email:

PowerReviews, Inc.  
1 N. Dearborn, Suite 800  
Chicago IL 60602  
privacy@powerreviews.com
